# ARTEM SEVASTOPOLSKY

artem.sevastopolsky@gmail.com \( +49 1520 5924403 \) \( \text{Web: seva100.github.io} \( \text{Scholar: fTSCTYQAAAAJ} \)

Computer Vision & AI researcher with 8+ years of experience working on diverse research & engineering projects. At the moment, a senior Ph.D. student at TUM (prof. Matthias Nießner) with a focus on 3D generative models and digital humans. Prior experience: Meta (Reality Labs; Codec Avatars lab, Pittsburgh, USA), Samsung (AI Center Moscow), Skoltech, medical imaging companies. 9 published papers, incl. at top-tier conferences (CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, WACV, 3DV). Citations: > 1300; h-index: 10.

#### Professional Experience

## Technical University of Munich (niessnerlab.org)

Research Scientist, PhD student

05/2021 - Present

- Worked on: 3D human head and hair modeling and reconstruction; face recognition with generative models.
- Published 2 papers as a first author (ICCV & 3DV), published 1 paper as a last author (WACV).
- 3 papers in submission (SIGGRAPH & ICCV).
- Supervised 3 Master's students, tutor at 3D Scanning & Motion Capture Masters-level course for 6 semesters.

## Meta (Reality Labs, Codec Avatars, Pittsburgh PA, USA)

Research Scientist Intern 06/2024 - 10/2024

- Worked on: Gaussian Reconstruction Models for one-shot Novel View Synthesis of human heads.
- Advanced existing models for the novel monocular streaming use case with SoTA results achieved.

#### Samsung AI Center Moscow

latest: Middle-level Deep Learning Engineer

01/2019 - 05/2021

- Worked on: 3D neural rendering, differentiable rendering; relightable human head portraits; human body texturing.
- Published 1 paper as a joint first author (3DV), 2 papers as a second author (CVPR & ECCV).
- Two US patents defended (#11961205), (#12229880).
- Supervised one research intern.

#### Youth Laboratories (today: Haut.AI)

Deep Learning Engineer

01/2017 - 05/2018

- Led an automated eye diseases diagnosis project.
- Main researcher of a skin wrinkles analysis project, launched with Nivea (Beiersdorf AG, Hamburg). Developed a segmentation network for skin wrinkles with partial supervision.
- Organized and supervised a hackathon Skinhack 2.0.

### Artec 3D (artec3d.com)

Deep Learning Intern

07/2016 - 09/2016

• Worked on: facial landmark detection from [RGB-]D images.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Technical University of Munich**

Munich, Germany

Ph.D. in Computer Science

2021 - Present

Topic: Human Face and Body Representation based on Deep Learning, prof. Matthias Nießner

### Skolkovo Insitute of Science and Technology

Moscow, Russia

M.Sc. in Computer Science

2019 - 2021

Topic: Learning image deformations via deep learning (thesis), prof. Victor Lempitsky, GPA 5.00 / 5.00 (max)

#### **Lomonosov Moscow State University**

Moscow, Russia

B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics & Informatics

2013 - 2017

Topic: Glaucoma detection methods based on deep neural networks, prof. Alexander D'yakonov, GPA 4.87 / 5.00

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINTS	
Avat3r: Large Animatable GRM for High-fidelity 3D He Kirschstein T., Romero J., Sevastopolsky A., Nießner M., Saito S.	
Gaussian Speech: Audio-Driven Gaussian Avatars (page Aneja S., Sevastopolsky A., Thies J., Dai A., Nießner M.	2024 in submission
HeadCraft: Modeling High-Detail Shape Variations for Sevastopolsky A., Grassal P., Giebenhain S., Athar S.R., Verdoliv	1 0
TriPlaneNet: An Encoder for EG3D Inversion (page) Bhattarai A.R., Nießner M., Sevastopolsky A.	2024 WACV
How to Boost Face Recognition with StyleGAN? (page) Sevastopolsky A., Malkov Y., Durasov N., Verdoliva L., Nießner	2023 M. ICCV
Relightable 3D Head Portraits from a Smartphone Video Sevastopolsky A., Ignatiev S., Ferrer G., Burnaev E., Lempitsky	
<b>TRANSPR: Transparency Ray-Accumulating Neural 3D</b> Kolos M.*, Sevastopolsky A.*, Lempitsky V.	Scene Point Renderer (page) 2020 3DV
Neural Point-Based Graphics (page) Aliev KA., Sevastopolsky A., Kolos M., Ulyanov D., Lempitsky	V. 2020 ECCV
Coordinate-based Texture Inpainting for Pose-Guided H Grigorev A., Sevastopolsky A., Vakhitov A., Lempitsky V.	fuman Image Generation (page) 2019 CVPR
Teaching	
3D Scanning & Motion Capture	Technical University of Munich
6 semesters. Per semester: $\sim$ 100 students, 6 final projects, example 100 students and 100 students are 100 students.	. 2022 - Present
Deep Learning	Skoltech
2 semesters. Per semester: $\sim$ 200 students, 5 final projects, exam	2020 - 2021
Theses & Guided Research Supervision	
Rachmadio Lazuardi, B.Sc.	Technical University of Munich; Beyond Presence
Dmitrii Pozdeev, B.Sc.	Technical University of Munich
	l University of Munich; currently: Bielefeld University
Maria Kolos, M.Sc.	Skoltech; currently: Samsung
Languages	
English	Full working proficiency
German	Limited working proficiency
Russian	Native

<sup>\*</sup> denotes equal contribution